{"Basic Career Skills":[{"question":"Which of the following is the key component of a resume?","option_a":"Travel History","option_b":"Work Experience","option_c":"Favorite Books","option_d":"Personal Anecdotes","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"For applying a job, your first preparation is ______.","option_a":"book a ticket to the interview place","option_b":"save money for expenses","option_c":"prepare a resume","option_d":"prepare for the interview","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the primary purpose of a cover letter?","option_a":"To list all your previous job responsibilities","option_b":"To introduce yourself and explain why you are a good fit for the job","option_c":"To provide a detailed personal biography","option_d":"To summarize your educational qualifications","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is an important step to take before sending your resume?","option_a":"Use complex words","option_b":"Focus only on technical skills","option_c":"Ensure details like phone number and email are correct","option_d":"Skip proofreading","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"The ability to connect well with people is known as _______.","option_a":"interpersonal skill","option_b":"leadership","option_c":"time management","option_d":"creativity","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"The ability to wait and stay calm is known as ______.","option_a":"creativity","option_b":"problem solving","option_c":"patience","option_d":"interpersonal skill","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Punctuality means _______","option_a":"done by punching machine","option_b":"informal","option_c":"politeness","option_d":"being on time","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Complete the sentence with appropriate word. \nThe Plumber _______ the tap.","option_a":"fit","option_b":"are fitting","option_c":"is fitting","option_d":"were fitting","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"When you borrow a pen from your classmate, what should you say?","option_a":"Give me your pen.","option_b":"Can you please give me a pen?","option_c":"I want a pen.","option_d":"I am taking your pen.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Magnificent, sharp, lengthy, bright, - are examples of ______","option_a":"describing words","option_b":"action words","option_c":"nouns","option_d":"pronouns","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Table, wire, socket, cable,  hammer, nail - are ______","option_a":"describing words","option_b":"pronouns","option_c":"naming words","option_d":"action words","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Fix, measure, pull, lift, grind, mix, operate - are examples of ______","option_a":"pronouns","option_b":"action words","option_c":"describing words","option_d":"naming words","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Comma, full stop, question mark are examples of _______","option_a":"design","option_b":"next paragraph","option_c":"formal communication","option_d":"punctuation mark","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"When you start a discussion on a topic, what do you say?","option_a":"Let you start","option_b":"Let me say","option_c":"Let us discuss","option_d":"Let us finish","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"While addressing your boss, you should be ______","option_a":"Impolite","option_b":"Informal","option_c":"Formal","option_d":"Expressive","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"You are requested to complete the given assignment by Monday This is an example of _______","option_a":"informal communication","option_b":"rude communication","option_c":"an order","option_d":"formal communication","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Gestures, facial expressions, eye contact are examples of _______","option_a":"verbal communication","option_b":"non-verbal communication","option_c":"oral communication","option_d":"written communication","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"‘Hi,’ ‘How are you?’, ‘What’s up?’ are examples of _______.","option_a":"formal communication","option_b":"informal communication","option_c":"polite communication","option_d":"impolite communication","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Complete the sentence with a suitable descriptive word: The roads in my town are in ________ condition.","option_a":"good","option_b":"expensive","option_c":"comfortable","option_d":"spacious","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Complete the sentence with a suitable describing word: There is a _________ garden with lovely flowers.","option_a":"expensive","option_b":"dim","option_c":"lots of","option_d":"beautiful","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Complete the sentence with a suitable describing word: There is a ________ playground near our house.","option_a":"older","option_b":"big","option_c":"dim","option_d":"shiny","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Complete the sentence with a suitable describing word:           \nThere are ________ apartments in my neighborhood.","option_a":"dim","option_b":"noise","option_c":"dull","option_d":"spacious","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Fill up the blanks with suitable words so as to become a meaningful sentence.\nThe Principal called Manoj and asked ______ to show ______ hall ticket for the CTS Examination.","option_a":"him, his","option_b":"him, her","option_c":"her, his","option_d":"her, him","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Fill up the blanks with suitable words so as to become a meaningful sentence  \nʺTell us about a difficult situation you have _______ and how you  _______ to come out of it.ʺ","option_a":"face, manage","option_b":"managed, face","option_c":"faced, manage","option_d":"faced, managed","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Complete the sentence with a suitable describing word.\nThere is a factory in the area. The air is ________.","option_a":"polluted","option_b":"boring","option_c":"uneven","option_d":"noisy","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Complete the sentence with a suitable describing word:\nThere is water scarcity in the locality. The area is ________.","option_a":"uneven","option_b":"noisy","option_c":"dry","option_d":"boring","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Complete the sentence with a suitable describing word:\nThe transportation to some rural areas is difficult as the roads are _________.","option_a":"dry","option_b":"polluted","option_c":"boring","option_d":"uneven","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one will help us to maintain the balance between mental and physical activities?","option_a":"Hobbies","option_b":"Laziness","option_c":"Stress","option_d":"Inactivity","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Important factors to check in a good resume are __________.","option_a":"paper quality","option_b":"company details","option_c":"Correct information, free from spelling and grammar mistakes","option_d":"attractive words","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a key factor for a well-organized resume?","option_a":"Complex designs","option_b":"Fancy fonts","option_c":"Simple designs and easy-to-read words","option_d":"Long paragraphs","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Spoken communication is usually not only _______ but also _______","option_a":"formal, informal","option_b":"verbal, nonverbal","option_c":"verbal, informal","option_d":"formal, nonverbal","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is a key component of a resume that outlines your relevant career experience and is used by experienced professionals?","option_a":"Resume Profile","option_b":"Resume Objective","option_c":"Work Experience","option_d":"Transferable Skills","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is NOT a key component of a resume?","option_a":"Relevant skills","option_b":"Additional information","option_c":"References","option_d":"Personal anecdotes","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Fill up the blanks with suitable words so as to become a meaningful sentence.\nThere _______ a coffee shop _______ the park.","option_a":"are, next to","option_b":"is, next to","option_c":"is, next","option_d":"are, next","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Fill up the blank with a suitable word so as to become a meaningful sentence.\nRainwater harvesting _______ to prevent water scarcity.","option_a":"gives","option_b":"gave","option_c":"help","option_d":"helps","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Fill up the blanks with suitable words so as to become a meaningful sentence.\nThere are many dos and don’ts to be ______ while preparing for/attending an __________","option_a":"there, interview","option_b":"identify, interview","option_c":"identified, interviewed","option_d":"identified, interview","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Miscommunication can lead to ________","option_a":"building relationships","option_b":"misunderstandings","option_c":"successful planning","option_d":"effective results","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is required for effective communication?","option_a":"Keep Listening","option_b":"Keep Talking","option_c":"Listen and talk carefully","option_d":"Listen carefully","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is included in the header section of a resume?","option_a":"Resume summary or objective","option_b":"Name, contact number, professional email ID, and address","option_c":"Career goals and achievements","option_d":"Relevant career experience","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Why is it important to understand the key components of a resume?","option_a":"To list your hobbies and interests","option_b":"To create a colorful design","option_c":"To showcase your unique skills, accomplishments, and potential","option_d":"To include personal anecdotes","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the process of formally introducing oneself called?","option_a":"Self-introduction","option_b":"Hiring","option_c":"Decision","option_d":"Seeking","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"The word ʹresumeʹ comes from French and means ________","option_a":"summary","option_b":"education","option_c":"experience","option_d":"placement","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following are included in a resume?","option_a":"Hobbies, favorite foods, and personal interests","option_b":"Childhood memories, dreams, and aspirations","option_c":"Daily routine, favorite movies, and vacation plans","option_d":"Contact information, educational details, skills and work experience","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"While applying for a job, the covering letter  should be easy to read by means of ______","option_a":"long descriptions.","option_b":"dividing the text into shorter paragraphs.","option_c":"increasing the font size.","option_d":"extra curricular activities.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"After preparing the resume, the next important step to do is _____","option_a":"sending the resume to the employer.","option_b":"writing an impressive cover letter.","option_c":"preparing for interview.","option_d":"applying for the job.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is very important to keep in mind while reviewing a resume?","option_a":"Salary details","option_b":"Lot of information to get the job","option_c":"Interest and hobbies","option_d":"Highlight skills and qualifications that match the job","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"While applying for a job, the important information that should be mentioned in the covering letter includes ______.","option_a":"salary expectations","option_b":"education details","option_c":"reasons of suitable for the role","option_d":"hobbies","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is formal communication?","option_a":"All written communication","option_b":"Official communication following a set of rules","option_c":"Talking with friends and family","option_d":"Casual chatting on social media","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a formal introduction in a job interview?","option_a":"ʺHey, nice to meet you!ʺ","option_b":"ʺHi, whats your name?ʺ","option_c":"ʺhello.. You can start the interview!ʺ","option_d":"ʺGood morning. Thank you for the opportunity.ʺ","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is an example of formal written communication?","option_a":"Texting a friend","option_b":"Sending a WhatsApp message","option_c":"Writing an email to your manager","option_d":"Posting on social media platforms","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"During a job interview, if you couldnʹt hear or understand a question, what would you say?","option_a":"ʺSorry! I didn’t understand. Could you please repeat the question?ʺ","option_b":"ʺHey, can you repeat that? I wasn’t paying attention.ʺ","option_c":"ʺI am lost. Can you say it again?ʺ","option_d":"ʺSpeak clearly and repeat the question.ʺ","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"During a job interview, which of the following responses shows good formal communication?","option_a":"ʺIʹm pretty good at a lot of things.ʺ","option_b":"ʺUh, I guess I can do a little bit of everything.ʺ","option_c":"ʺMy top three skills are problem-solving, teamwork, and attention to detail.ʺ","option_d":"ʺI donʹt know, I never really thought about it.ʺ","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is ʺinformal communicationʺ?","option_a":"All verbal communication","option_b":"Official communication following a set of rules","option_c":"Casual conversations outside of official work arrangements","option_d":"Talking at official meetings","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is an informal situation within the workplace?","option_a":"Working with files","option_b":"Working on a desktop","option_c":"Working on a laptop","option_d":"Having a meal in the office canteen","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What are some advantages of informal communication at the workplace?","option_a":"Helps people work together better","option_b":"Makes things more official at work","option_c":"Creates a strict environment at work","option_d":"Makes people talk less","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"One of the informations in an informal conversation with a co-worker is _________","option_a":"asking about their roles in the company.","option_b":"asking about their house.","option_c":"asking about their experience.","option_d":"asking about the office timing.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"If a co-worker asks for a support with a task, proper way of responding is _________","option_a":"ask, you donʹt even know this much?","option_b":"i am too busy right now.","option_c":"sure, I can help. What do you need?","option_d":"send a formal request via email.","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is workplace etiquette?","option_a":"Everyday manners outside of work","option_b":"Proper behaviour and workplace professionalism","option_c":"Casual behaviour with colleagues","option_d":"Gossiping","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is considered as appropriate workplace behaviour?","option_a":"Being late to work regularly","option_b":"Interrupting others during meetings","option_c":"Talking loudly on the phone","option_d":"Maintaining a clean workspace","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following skills would be most beneficial to add to your resume?","option_a":"Leadership Qualities","option_b":"Laziness","option_c":"Procrastination","option_d":"Indifference","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following actions in an official meeting shows appropriate workplace etiquette?","option_a":"Checking  phone and respond to messages","option_b":"Chatting with coworkers","option_c":"Interrupt the speaker in meeting","option_d":"Keeping the phone on silent mode and actively participate in the discussion","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"If coworkers are gossiping about another coworker, what you should do?","option_a":"Feel that gossiping is inappropriate workplace behaviour","option_b":"Join the conversation and continue","option_c":"Tell another coworker about the gossip","option_d":"Listen to the gossip","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following statements shows good teamwork?","option_a":"Keeping all ideas to yourself","option_b":"Criticizing teammatesʹ efforts","option_c":"Working together towards a common goal","option_d":"Ignoring othersʹ ideas and opinions","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is required for teamwork?","option_a":"Proper communication","option_b":"Money","option_c":"Conflict and Argument","option_d":"Easy tasks","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"While working on a project with other teammates, which of these make as a good team player?","option_a":"Getting angry when others donʹt listen","option_b":"Sharing ideas to help the team work faster","option_c":"Thinking we never make a mistake","option_d":"Not listening to teammates ideas and opinions","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Your team has completed a challenging project successfully. How should you celebrate the success?","option_a":"Say you did everything and donʹt praise others","option_b":"Blame the group for any errors","option_c":"Donʹt celebrate and start the next job","option_d":"Thank everyone in your group for helping","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"If a teammate is struggling to complete their assigned task, what should you do?","option_a":"Ignore their struggle and focus on your own tasks","option_b":"Offer to help and support them to complete their task","option_c":"Criticize them for not being efficient","option_d":"Complain to the superior about their lack of contribution","answer":"B","notes":""}],"Future Work Skills":[{"question":"_______ is influenced by rapid change in technology","option_a":"Future of work","option_b":"Nature of work","option_c":"Workforce","option_d":"Working capital","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following ways you should use to improve your technology skills?","option_a":"Handwork","option_b":"Playing","option_c":"Social service","option_d":"Social media, Online digital tools","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"ʺGigʺ economy is ______","option_a":"A system of work where people work in part-time","option_b":"Indian economy","option_c":"Foreign economy","option_d":"Regular job","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"__________ are a great way for gig workers to find jobs.","option_a":"Employment exchange","option_b":"Online platforms and Apps","option_c":"Employment news paper","option_d":"Placement cell","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which among the following is self-employment idea?","option_a":"Freelance tailoring Service","option_b":"Boutique owner","option_c":"Home catering service","option_d":"All the options","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Migration of work means _______","option_a":"shifting the industry","option_b":"going to a different place to find a job","option_c":"shifting of profession","option_d":"working in different shifts","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Important factor to consider before migrating include _______.","option_a":"easy job","option_b":"tourist place","option_c":"cost of living","option_d":"freedom","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Skill India Digital is _________","option_a":"a digital Movie","option_b":"a platform for learning and career resource","option_c":"central govt. office","option_d":"name of a trade","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Create a digital CV and share it with a QR code is _________","option_a":"your digital identity","option_b":"digital marketing","option_c":"entrepreneurship","option_d":"interview skill","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Separating paper and plastic from bio waste before throwing them away is ________","option_a":"creativity","option_b":"green mindset","option_c":"innovation","option_d":"profession","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Good practice for green mind set is _________.","option_a":"taking a lot of printouts","option_b":"using air conditioners all the time","option_c":"keeping lights on all the time","option_d":"separating and recycling waste","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"________ is a time when you, your family, and your teacher meet and interact to understand and support each other better.","option_a":"Family engagement","option_b":"Family tour","option_c":"Family meeting","option_d":"Family income","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following future workplace skills is likely to have less importance?","option_a":"Working from home","option_b":"Working with digital tools","option_c":"Working hours strictly between 9 AM to 5 PM","option_d":"Adapting to new technology","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What does a workplace look like after a pandemic like covid?","option_a":"Mix of work from home and office","option_b":"Empty space","option_c":"Less employees","option_d":"Less production","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is an app-based gig economy platform that helps people find part-time jobs?","option_a":"Permanent employee","option_b":"Independent contractor","option_c":"Home catering","option_d":"Swiggy","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a regular, non-app-based gig economy job opportunity?","option_a":"Uber","option_b":"Dunzo","option_c":"Home catering","option_d":"Swiggy","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"How have workplaces changed after COVID?","option_a":"No focus on technology","option_b":"Flexible in working hours is nil","option_c":"Mix of in-person and at-home work","option_d":"Less job opportunities","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which is an example of being open to learning in the workplace?","option_a":"Refusing to attend training sessions to improve technology skills","option_b":"Accepting and adapting to changes in work processes","option_c":"Avoiding feedback from colleagues","option_d":"Ignoring advancements in technology","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"An important skill required for the future of work is _______.","option_a":"Learning to make reels and TikTok videos.","option_b":"Avoiding learning new skills.","option_c":"Mastering internet skills.","option_d":"Avoiding building professional relationships.","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is an important future workplace skill for employees?","option_a":"Doing paperwork","option_b":"Doing manual work","option_c":"Networking and relationship-building","option_d":"Planning holidays","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"When a person joined a new company, he may be nervous using digital tablets provided at work. That time he shall ________","option_a":"Complain to his manager.","option_b":"Ask his coworkers to do all the digital work.","option_c":"Quit his job.","option_d":"Keep an open mind and ask his coworkers to teach him.","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the gig economy?","option_a":"A system where employees work full-time for a single employer","option_b":"A system where workers take on part-time or temporary jobs","option_c":"A system where workers are paid a fixed monthly salary","option_d":"A system where workers have fixed work hours and locations","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which option below describes a ʺgigʺ in the gig economy?","option_a":"A job with full-time hours and benefits","option_b":"A typical 9-5 job","option_c":"A specific task or project","option_d":"No specific task","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"A _______ helps gig workers find customers and provide services at a fixed charge.","option_a":"netflix","option_b":"platform/app","option_c":"school","option_d":"bank","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"To become a gig worker, a person should find gig work opportunities by means of _______","option_a":"Finding a multinational company.","option_b":"Connecting with friends, people you might know, and groups in your community.","option_c":"Independently searching for a job.","option_d":"Studying about gig work.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"A skilled electrician searching gig work that matches his skill will find job opportunities in _______","option_a":"Amazon for selling products online","option_b":"Zoom for video calls","option_c":"Uber for driving people","option_d":"Urban Company for offering home repair services","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What does self-employment mean?","option_a":"Working for a single employer","option_b":"Working independently and earning directly from your work","option_c":"Receiving a fixed monthly salary","option_d":"Working part-time from home","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What is the benefit of self-employment?","option_a":"Directly earning from your work","option_b":"Fixed working hours","option_c":"Monthly salary payment","option_d":"Limited control over your tasks","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which is an example of a self-employment?","option_a":"Working full-time at a company","option_b":"Driving for a taxi company","option_c":"Being a student at a university","option_d":"Teaching subjects or skills as a personal tutor","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"How can you become self-employed?","option_a":"Join an MBA course","option_b":"Try your idea on a small scale and join relevant short term course","option_c":"Work in a company","option_d":"Rely solely on luck","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Someone loves photography and dreams of starting his own photography business. They should start with _______.","option_a":"buying the latest photography equipment, even if it is beyond their budget.","option_b":"taking random pictures and sharing them online.","option_c":"learning more about photography and joining a basic photography course.","option_d":"starting advertising without any planning.","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What does migrating for work mean?","option_a":"Staying in the same place for work","option_b":"Changing jobs within the same city","option_c":"Moving to a different place to find a job","option_d":"Working from home","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is a common reason for people to migrate for work?","option_a":"To learn new languages","option_b":"To find better job opportunities","option_c":"To spend time with family","option_d":"To explore new places","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What would be the first step if some one plans to move to a different city for work?","option_a":"Move to new place and search for job.","option_b":"Apply for loan in bank.","option_c":"Ask money from relatives and friends.","option_d":"Find how much it will cost to travel and live there; earn and save.","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"If you want to work in a foreign country, to migrate safely, you have to _______","option_a":"Learn about the place, confirm the job before moving.","option_b":"Move and ask for confirmation.","option_c":"Leave to foreign country without informing anyone.","option_d":"Think how you spend your money.","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"If you have to migrate from your place to a new city to join a new job, what will you do to migrate safely?","option_a":"Research about living in the new city","option_b":"Always share exact location on social media","option_c":"Buy gifts for neighbours","option_d":"Believe everything brokers say","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What is the main purpose of the Skill India Digital Platform?","option_a":"To offer offline training programs","option_b":"To provide financial assistance for job seekers","option_c":"To facilitate online learning and skill development","option_d":"To promote international job opportunities","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"How can users access the Skill India Digital Platform?","option_a":"Only through offline training centers","option_b":"Only on a specific type of device","option_c":"Through a specialized learning app","option_d":"On computers, tablets, and phones","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which section of the Skill India Digital Platform helps users find physical training centers nearby?","option_a":"Skill courses","option_b":"Job Exchange","option_c":"Centres","option_d":"Recommendations","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What type of resources one can find in the Skill India Digital Platform?","option_a":"Only job listings","option_b":"Courses, skill centers, job opportunities, and more","option_c":"Only eBooks and reading materials","option_d":"Financial services and government schemes","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"To learn digital marketing in the Skill India Digital Platform, we have to ________","option_a":"search for job opportunities.","option_b":"enroll in any course available.","option_c":"explore the skill courses section.","option_d":"find a physical training center.","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"A green practice involves any activity that ________","option_a":"causes harm to the environment.","option_b":"protects and takes care of the environment and resources.","option_c":"involves consuming too much.","option_d":"generates pollution.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which term describes using things in a way that can last for a long time without causing harm?","option_a":"Sustainability","option_b":"Pollution","option_c":"Eco-friendliness","option_d":"Resources","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What does having a green mindset mean?","option_a":"Making choices that harm the environment","option_b":"Using resources without considering sustainability","option_c":"Ignoring pollution and waste management","option_d":"Caring for the environment and using resources wisely","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Green practice means _______","option_a":"buying unnecessary items.","option_b":"leaving lights and fans on when leaving a room.","option_c":"carrying a cloth bag to buy groceries.","option_d":"buying single-use plastic water bottles.","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"While going for a picnic with friends, you have been asked to bring disposable plates and cups. With green mind set, your action will be ________","option_a":"say yes and bring disposable plates and cups.","option_b":"bring reusable plates and cups.","option_c":"ignore the invite to the picnic.","option_d":"bring green color disposable plates and cups.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What are green jobs?","option_a":"Jobs shared in green colours","option_b":"Jobs that harm the environment","option_c":"Jobs that ignore waste separation and recycling","option_d":"Jobs that conserve resources and help the environment","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a green practice?","option_a":"Using high power air conditioners","option_b":"Using plastic containers","option_c":"Not separating recycle waste","option_d":"Grow plants wherever possible","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"A green workplace _______","option_a":"Uses less paper and energy-saving lights.","option_b":"Uses disposable items and plastic water bottles.","option_c":"Keeps the lights on all the time.","option_d":"Ignores waste separation and recycling.","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Suggestion for green practices in the office canteen is ______","option_a":"Delivering food in plastic packaging.","option_b":"Using steel plates and cups.","option_c":"Providing lunch to the staff in disposable plates.","option_d":"Serve green vegetables.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"A beauty parlor staff follows environment-friendly actions by means of  _______.","option_a":"using plastic gloves.","option_b":"using plastic cups.","option_c":"discarding consumable items.","option_d":"using non plastic materials, disposing wastes in an environmentally friendly way.","answer":"D","notes":""}],"Internet Skills":[{"question":"A computer system consists of __________","option_a":"software and program","option_b":"hardware and software","option_c":"mouse and keyboard","option_d":"circuit diagram","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"A software application used to enable computer users to locate and access web page is called ___________","option_a":"web browser","option_b":"web server","option_c":"website","option_d":"email","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"An illegal activity committed on the internet is called ___________","option_a":"virus","option_b":"cyber crime","option_c":"search engine","option_d":"social networking","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"In an email, where will you add the recipientʹs email address to whom you want to send the copy of an email?","option_a":"To","option_b":"CC","option_c":"Bcc","option_d":"Subject","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is a cyber crime?","option_a":"Sending email","option_b":"Online purchasing","option_c":"Online gambling","option_d":"Chatting with friends","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is a search engine?","option_a":"Flicker","option_b":"Hotmail","option_c":"Facebook","option_d":"Google","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is a social networking site?","option_a":"Outlook express","option_b":"Facebook","option_c":"Lotus notes","option_d":"Mozilla","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is a web browser?","option_a":"Facebook","option_b":"Hotmail","option_c":"Internet explorer","option_d":"Outlook express","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which among the following is not an Online payment application?","option_a":"Google Pay","option_b":"BHIM UPI","option_c":"Banking Applications","option_d":"Instagram","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"A wireless technology that connects a laptop to the internet is called _______.","option_a":"Bluetooth","option_b":"Wi-Fi","option_c":"Source Network","option_d":"Desktop","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Shortcut keys Ctrl+C, Ctrl+V, Ctrl+S mean _______","option_a":"save, cut, copy","option_b":"cut, save, copy","option_c":"copy, paste, save","option_d":"cut, copy, save","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"The conversion of computer data from one format to another is called ______","option_a":"pasting","option_b":"copying","option_c":"cutting","option_d":"Data conversion","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is called a media presentation shared over the Internet?","option_a":"Live media","option_b":"Live telecast","option_c":"Webcast","option_d":"Seminar","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is the standard way in which computers connect wirelessly?","option_a":"Wi-Fi","option_b":"WAN","option_c":"LAN","option_d":"ISP","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which wireless technology standard is used for exchanging data between fixed and mobile devices over short distance?","option_a":"Router","option_b":"Bluetooth","option_c":"Pen drive","option_d":"CD/DVD","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which app is widely used for screen casting from your mobile phone?","option_a":"WhatsApp","option_b":"Facebook","option_c":"Webcast","option_d":"Mobizen","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"______________ is a file storage and synchronization service of cloud computing developed by Google.","option_a":"Internet Explorer","option_b":"Google Drive","option_c":"Netflix","option_d":"Hard disc","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"A secure Wi-Fi is one ______.","option_a":"that allows everyone to connect","option_b":"that is open to the public","option_c":"that has a password to login","option_d":"that is opened by landline","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Alexa, Google, Siri are in the category of _______","option_a":"Musical instruments","option_b":"Voice recognition devices","option_c":"Voice recorders","option_d":"Translation devices","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Full form of GPS is _______","option_a":"Globe Pointing System","option_b":"Great Polar System","option_c":"Global Positioning System","option_d":"Global Planning System","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"We use Google maps to follow the _______ to reach a place.","option_a":"destination","option_b":"distance","option_c":"demark","option_d":"direction","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"When we want to type using our voice, we are using _______","option_a":"voice of google","option_b":"voice recognition feature","option_c":"voicing technique","option_d":"voice recorder","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"The ability of a computer or machine to mimic the capabilities of the human mind is called ________","option_a":"artificial intelligence","option_b":"intellect","option_c":"artificial performer","option_d":"natural intelligence","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"A resume should be _______","option_a":"having long and detailed information","option_b":"short and precise","option_c":"bold and colourful","option_d":"having acronyms and abbreviation","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What should be entered in the ʹToʹ field when drafting an email?","option_a":"The subject of the email","option_b":"The recipientʹs email address","option_c":"Your own email address","option_d":"The main message content","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"The physical part of a computer is called ________","option_a":"software","option_b":"hardware","option_c":"malware","option_d":"spyware","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"_________ is an activity where students who finished their studies from institute and come to talk to the present students.","option_a":"Alumni Engagement","option_b":"Job mela","option_c":"Campus interview","option_d":"Conference","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"The practice of using a network of remote servers hosted on the internet to store, manage and process data is called _______","option_a":"Cloud computing","option_b":"Search engine","option_c":"Google","option_d":"Yahoo","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is the input device among the options?","option_a":"Monitor","option_b":"Printer","option_c":"Speaker","option_d":"Keyboard","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is essentially required to receive communication by Email?","option_a":"Desktop","option_b":"Printer","option_c":"Email account","option_d":"Laptop","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"When searching for new information on Google, why is it important to use the right words?","option_a":"To find correct and useful information","option_b":"To change the color of the search page","option_c":"To make the screen brighter","option_d":"To learn a new language","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"After collecting useful information for a project work, what will be the next step to do?","option_a":"Mix up all the information","option_b":"Share all the information with coworkers","option_c":"Read thoroughly the information and mark the important points","option_d":"Keep the information in separate folders","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"For a project work you have collected some information from internet and sorted it. What is the best way to share it with your team?","option_a":"Tell everything in detail","option_b":"Share only the main points clearly, use simple words and pictures, if possible","option_c":"Talk about information which are not available","option_d":"Print all the information and give it to the team members.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Why is it good to think about what you learn?","option_a":"Itʹs a good time pass","option_b":"It helps to remember and understand better.","option_c":"It improves handwriting.","option_d":"It makes you look busy.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While thinking about learning, what are the questions you can ask yourself?","option_a":"Its waste of time","option_b":"It is very tough","option_c":"How can I learn and understand  better?","option_d":"It is very difficult for me to understand","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is a job portal?","option_a":"A building where you go to find work","option_b":"A place where you can play games and talk to friends","option_c":"A special room where job interviews happen online","option_d":"A website where companies post jobs and people can search and apply for them","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What should you always remember when creating your profile on a job portal?","option_a":"To include skills required for the job, even if you donʹt have them","option_b":"To use a fake name","option_c":"To always be truthful","option_d":"To leave out important information","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Checking the skills required is important before applying for a job, because ________","option_a":"To be sure you can do the job well.","option_b":"To chat with friends about it.","option_c":"To impress the interviewer.","option_d":"It is not important to check the skills required for a job.","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"You are a trained electrician. If you want to get a job in Delhi, what are the key words you use to search in job portal?","option_a":"Electrician job","option_b":"Delhi job","option_c":"Electrician jobs in Delhi","option_d":"Electrician training","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"If you want to apply for jobs through Naukri.com,  what you will do?","option_a":"Select all the cities where jobs are available","option_b":"Match the skills with the job description","option_c":"Apply to all the jobs listed","option_d":"Ignore the job descriptions","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While applying for a job through email, what are the documents need to be attached?","option_a":"Birth certificate","option_b":"Resume, Course and Training Certificates","option_c":"Address Proof","option_d":"Photographs from childhood","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While writing an email, why it is important to state the subject clearly?","option_a":"Email cannot be sent without a subject line","option_b":"To tell the company what the email is about","option_c":"To show he has good English skills","option_d":"Subject should not be left blank","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While applying for a job, how to start an email to a company?","option_a":"Start with a joke","option_b":"Attach favorite photos","option_c":"Begin with a clear subject line and a polite greeting","option_d":"Write a short story about hobbies","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"While sending a job application through email, how to share the resume and other documents?","option_a":"Click photos from phone and send it","option_b":"Should not send documents over email as it is not safe","option_c":"Copying and pasting the content of the documents into the email body","option_d":"Attach the scanned documents as pdf with the email","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"While applying for a position as fitter, which of the following email subject lines would be the most suitable?","option_a":"Fitter Job needed","option_b":"Applying for a new Job","option_c":"Urgent Attention Needed","option_d":"Application for Fitter Position - [Your Name]","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"How can linkedIn help you in finding a job?","option_a":"Its economical","option_b":"Connecting you with company, professionals faster","option_c":"Its available in mobile","option_d":"As informed by others","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"The reason to reply to comments on your YouTube videos is _______","option_a":"to get more videos","option_b":"make viewers feel connected","option_c":"to use the internet","option_d":"to get more friends","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"You are a talented carpenter. In what way it will help your work on YouTube video?","option_a":"It allows people to see your carpentry skills and appreciate your expertise","option_b":"Just a time pass","option_c":"Many related videos are available","option_d":"Its a hobby","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"You have bakery business. Using WhatsApp, what way it will help your Business?","option_a":"Chat with friends","option_b":"Quickly respond to customer orders and questions","option_c":"Watch baking tutorial videos","option_d":"Check status updates","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"You have an Instagram page for jewellery business. What should you do to connect with viewers?","option_a":"Post dance reels","option_b":"Post about a T.V. show you like","option_c":"Share daily updates about your business as Stories on social media","option_d":"Post cooking videos","answer":"C","notes":""}],"Professional Skills":[{"question":"What is a benefit of self-improvement?","option_a":"Better relationships","option_b":"Increased workload","option_c":"Lower confidence","option_d":"Stagnation","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"For career growth and _________ we need to build ______","option_a":"skills, sustainability","option_b":"skills, bridges","option_c":"sustainability, dams","option_d":"sustainability, new skills","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What will keep evolving there by making jobs undergo changes?","option_a":"Time","option_b":"Workforce","option_c":"Technology","option_d":"Investment","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is required for your career growth and sustainability?","option_a":"Good behaviour","option_b":"Degree","option_c":"Opportunity","option_d":"Build new skills","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What has drastically changed the world of work?","option_a":"Environment","option_b":"Technology","option_c":"Investment","option_d":"Workers","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"A person can get promotions based on his _______ and _________","option_a":"environment, experience","option_b":"example, qualifications","option_c":"qualifications, experience","option_d":"conduct, behaviour","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is work ethic?","option_a":"Skills for work","option_b":"Moral values at work","option_c":"Physical labor","option_d":"Measuring productivity","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Learning a new skill to do fundamentally the same nature of task is called _______","option_a":"Reskilling","option_b":"Upskilling","option_c":"Semi-skilled","option_d":"Technician","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"A person’s natural ability to do something is called ______","option_a":"attitude","option_b":"adaptability","option_c":"aptitude","option_d":"acceptance","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Plan, Prepare, Perform is related to ______.","option_a":"your resume","option_b":"your work","option_c":"attending an interview","option_d":"your personality","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Why is a strong work ethic important?","option_a":"More vacations","option_b":"Slower work","option_c":"Efficient productivity","option_d":"Less teamwork","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a good working habit?","option_a":"Complaining about coworkers","option_b":"Arriving late to work","option_c":"Dressing neatly","option_d":"Ignoring tasks","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is a good habit regarding your behavior towards coworkers?","option_a":"Ignore them","option_b":"Complain behind their backs","option_c":"Treat them with respect","option_d":"Avoid interaction","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"___________ is a code of behaviour that is based on respect, values and professionalism.","option_a":"Workplace etiquette","option_b":"Business","option_c":"Education","option_d":"Experience","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What does being punctual at work signify?","option_a":"Carelessness","option_b":"Professionalism","option_c":"Laziness","option_d":"Disinterest","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"_______  is when a group of people work together to finish something.","option_a":"Team work","option_b":"Business","option_c":"Education","option_d":"Experience","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following best describes skills such as commitment, reliability, adaptability and flexibility?","option_a":"Teamwork","option_b":"Self-management","option_c":"Business","option_d":"Education","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"________ is always doing our work with dedication and to the best of our ability.","option_a":"Self-management","option_b":"Reliability","option_c":"Commitment","option_d":"Honesty","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What should you avoid in your appearance at work?","option_a":"Wearing clean clothes","option_b":"Wrinkled clothes","option_c":"Neat appearance","option_d":"Proper uniform","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a people skills required in a workplace?","option_a":"Driving skills","option_b":"Being kind & Listening","option_c":"Technical Skills","option_d":"Work alone","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following ways can help you work well with people?","option_a":"Technical skill","option_b":"Not doing any mistakes","option_c":"Not talking to coworkers","option_d":"Paying attention, staying calm in challenging situations","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which is a good way to handle when some of your team member made a mistake?","option_a":"Blame the person who did the mistake","option_b":"Wait for someone else to solve it","option_c":"Discuss and find a way to solve it","option_d":"Get angry and scold the team","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"While working with your team on a project, one of your coworkers is finding it difficult to finish their job. What should you do in this situation?","option_a":"Finish their work for them.","option_b":"Ignore their problem and focus on your own work.","option_c":"Complain about them to the boss.","option_d":"Help and support them to finish their work.","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"When your teamʹs project is unsuccessful, what will you do as a leader?","option_a":"Blame the team for the failure","option_b":"Encourage learning from mistakes","option_c":"Scold them","option_d":"Ignore the team members","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What does working well together mean?","option_a":"Be friendly with all","option_b":"Not doing any mistakes","option_c":"Participate get-together","option_d":"Sharing ideas, listening, finding solutions together","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following behaviours is not a characteristic of a team player?","option_a":"Taking credit for othersʹ work","option_b":"Listening to teammatesʹ ideas","option_c":"Respecting different viewpoints","option_d":"Willingness to help others","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"In a team where members have different ideas and there is a disagreement, what should be done?","option_a":"Let them argue","option_b":"Choose one idea without discussion","option_c":"Discuss both ideas and find a way to make everyone agree","option_d":"Ask someone else to decide","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What term describes a person who is always trying out new ways to reuse waste materials?","option_a":"Planner","option_b":"Doer","option_c":"Idea Person","option_d":"Peacekeeper","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of these situations show people working well together as a team?","option_a":"Two people arguing and not agreeing","option_b":"A group sharing ideas and listening to each other","option_c":"One person doing all the work without any help from team members","option_d":"All are working without discussing each other","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is self-management skills?","option_a":"Listening skill","option_b":"Writing skill","option_c":"Adaptability and Flexibility","option_d":"Speaking skill","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following best describes the self-management skill of reliability?","option_a":"Not completing tasks on time","option_b":"People always trust you to do your job well","option_c":"Ignoring the needs of others","option_d":"Not being honest with colleagues","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"When a machine operator suddenly faces a problem and quickly finds another way to do the work, it is called _________.","option_a":"Honesty","option_b":"Adaptability","option_c":"Sincerity","option_d":"Integrity","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While working in a team, if one of your team members is on leave and hasnʹt completed their tasks, what should you do?","option_a":"Criticise your coworker for not completing their work.","option_b":"Keep working on your own tasks.","option_c":"Ask other team members for help and complete your coworkerʹs task.","option_d":"Complain to your supervisor about the incomplete work.","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"While working on a project, you realized that you had made a mistake. What should you do?","option_a":"Blame team members for the mistake","option_b":"Wait for someone else to find out about the mistake","option_c":"Tell your boss about the mistake","option_d":"Ignore the mistake and continue working","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"While doing some difficult work, if it is not going on well, what we have to do?","option_a":"Keep trying and look for another way","option_b":"Take a break and give up","option_c":"Ask someone else to do it for you","option_d":"Get upset and quit trying","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"While working with a team, if we notice a co-worker struggling with their workload, what should we do?","option_a":"Ignore their struggles and focus on your own work.","option_b":"Offer to help them with their tasks.","option_c":"Laugh at their inability to manage their workload.","option_d":"Report their struggles to the supervisor.","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a good work habit?","option_a":"Getting tensed when work is challenging","option_b":"Not following workplace rules","option_c":"Choosing easy tasks","option_d":"Not giving up when something goes wrong","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"When we find a faster way to pack products at the factory, what should we do?","option_a":"Pack products faster than our coworkers","option_b":"Continue packing the way the team has been doing","option_c":"Share the faster packing method with our team","option_d":"Keep the method as secret","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"As a machine operator, if you find that your machine is not working properly, what should you do?","option_a":"Ignore it","option_b":"Try to find the cause and remedies for the problem to solve it","option_c":"Blame someone for the defect","option_d":"Hide the machine","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Why is it important to think of new ways to solve problems?","option_a":"New ideas can make work easier or faster","option_b":"It is fun to try new things","option_c":"To waste time","option_d":"It is unnecessary to try new things","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What should you do before making a choice at work?","option_a":"Don’t think too much","option_b":"Look at the details, listen to othersʹ ideas and choose","option_c":"Take immediate decision","option_d":"Don’t discuss with others","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While working, it is important to share our ideas with others because _______","option_a":"to make others feel included.","option_b":"to show off your knowledge.","option_c":"talking can help and make ideas better.","option_d":"to impress others.","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"In a manufacturing unit, the packaging process is taking longer than usual time, causing delays in shipments. What should the workers do?","option_a":"Continue packaging the same way","option_b":"Ignore the problem","option_c":"Discuss and think about different ways to pack faster","option_d":"Complain to the management","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"While purchasing an equipment for your trade, how will you make decision?","option_a":"Choose the cheapest machine available","option_b":"Look at all the details, think carefully about the needs & budget and then make the choice","option_c":"Pick the machine which you like","option_d":"Choose the first machine you see","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What are some resource related problems in a workplace?","option_a":"Electricity","option_b":"Less operators","option_c":"More space for less machines","option_d":"Shortage of materials and space","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What are some people related problems in a workplace?","option_a":"More staff in the workplace","option_b":"More qualified workers","option_c":"More experienced works","option_d":"Workers do not communicate while facing the problem","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"In an organization where all workers are skilled and working systematically, the outcome will be ________.","option_a":"Loss for the organisation","option_b":"Confusion","option_c":"Increased output and profit","option_d":"Less work gets done","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"If a factory manager gets a big order to deliver but there is a shortage of workers, the manager will _______","option_a":"Stop working","option_b":"Request workers to work extra hours","option_c":"Ignore the problem","option_d":"Cancel the orders","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"When you do not know how to use a new machine, what will be your action?","option_a":"Ask for help and learn how to use the machine","option_b":"Take a break and do it later","option_c":"Stay silent till someone teaches you","option_d":"Leave the job","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What are the different steps in design thinking?","option_a":"Imagine, Plan and Try","option_b":"Try, Create and Decide","option_c":"Listen, Choose, Plan, Try, Ask","option_d":"Imagine, Decide, Create and Try","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"How does design thinking help solve problems?","option_a":"By following a strict process","option_b":"By guessing solutions randomly","option_c":"By understanding what people need and improving solutions","option_d":"By trusting on personal assumptions","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"If you come up with an idea to improve the work using design thinking, what should you do next?","option_a":"Write down your idea and keep it safe","option_b":"Apply and test if it works","option_c":"Tell everyone about it","option_d":"Think of another idea","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While purchasing new chairs for students using design thinking, what is the first step to think?","option_a":"Plan how to make the chair","option_b":"Think what is studentʹs requirement in a chair","option_c":"Choose the colour of the chair","option_d":"Test different chair designs","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"When a manufacturer is trying to make a better school bag using design thinking, what would be the next step after understanding the studentsʹ needs in a bag?","option_a":"Plan different bag designs","option_b":"Ask students to test the bags","option_c":"Choose the material for the bag","option_d":"Choose the colour of the bag","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"If your first design of design thinking doesnʹt work, what should you do?","option_a":"Give up on it","option_b":"Ask for feedback and try to improve","option_c":"Make something else","option_d":"Purchase some other design","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What should a restaurant owner do to attract more customers and improve his business?","option_a":"Guess what customers want and provide it.","option_b":"Copy other restaurants and follow.","option_c":"Talk to customers, understand their preferences, make changes to the menu, and ask for feedback.","option_d":"Randomly select new dishes in the menu","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"If you are making a new app for the people, why it is important to test it?","option_a":"To show people how good you are at making apps","option_b":"To check if people like the colors and pictures","option_c":"Because itʹs fun to watch others try your app","option_d":"To see how people use it and make it better","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"A bag manufacturer designs a product and shows it to five different people for feedback. Why is it important to listen to different users and not just one?","option_a":"Because itʹs fun","option_b":"To get a lot of ideas","option_c":"To understand the common problems from different users","option_d":"To get a lot of appreciation for her work","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Your community wants to reduce plastic waste. How can you use design thinking to find new ideas to solve this problem?","option_a":"Ignore the problem because itʹs too difficult to solve","option_b":"Work together with shops or people nearby to find ways to use less plastic","option_c":"Make more things with plastic because theyʹre easy to use","option_d":"Blame others for the plastic waste issue","answer":"B","notes":""}],"Entrepreneurial Skills":[{"question":"A person who is associated with the starting of a business is called _______","option_a":"Merchant","option_b":"Entrepreneur","option_c":"Businessman","option_d":"Sales Executive","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Entrepreneurship is also termed as ______","option_a":"Employer","option_b":"Employment seeker","option_c":"Self-employment","option_d":"Investor","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Believing that you have the capability to achieve your dreams is called ______","option_a":"Self-awareness","option_b":"Grit","option_c":"Self belief","option_d":"Independent decision making","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Working hard to achieve your goals and not giving up when you face failure is called _______","option_a":"Independent decision making","option_b":"Self-belief","option_c":"Self-awareness","option_d":"Grit","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What should a business owner do to retain customers in a competitive market?","option_a":"Lower their prices to match competitors","option_b":"Identify and understand their customersʹ needs and preferences","option_c":"Focus solely on superior quality without considering customer feedback","option_d":"Offer a wider variety of products without any market research","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"Which one is a key skill to be used for a Market survey?","option_a":"Communication","option_b":"Computer knowledge","option_c":"MBA Degree","option_d":"Appearance","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What are three important elements to remember while conducting a survey?","option_a":"Listen, observe, tell","option_b":"Observe, record, learn","option_c":"Listen, observe, learn","option_d":"Talk, learn, understand","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"____________ are at the centre of any business.","option_a":"Working capital","option_b":"Bank loan","option_c":"Licence","option_d":"Customers","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is a phase that should be completed before starting the promotional campaign?","option_a":"Designing advertisements","option_b":"Establishing direct marketing strategies","option_c":"Defining the product, its price, and the place of sale","option_d":"Planning public relations events","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Taking decisions on your own, after carefully thinking about them is the quality of _______","option_a":"Self-awareness","option_b":"Self-belief","option_c":"Grit","option_d":"Independent decision making","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"One important rule to network effectively is ______","option_a":"talk to the same people","option_b":"focus on selling your product","option_c":"keep in touch with your contacts","option_d":"identify your competitors","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"If you want to give people relevant information about you and your business in an easy way, you will ______","option_a":"write on a piece of paper and give","option_b":"ask them to search on Google","option_c":"verbally tell them when they ask","option_d":"give them your business card","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Anitha started an Instagram page for her craft business. She used _________ marketing strategy.","option_a":"Online","option_b":"Taglines","option_c":"Poster","option_d":"Networking","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"Human resources are __________","option_a":"Human right activists","option_b":"your customers","option_c":"your staff","option_d":"your competitors","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Which of the following is not a resource?","option_a":"Raw materials","option_b":"Customer database","option_c":"Finished products","option_d":"Loss in business","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"You are a lifelong learner if you _______","option_a":"get a PhD","option_b":"keep growing and adding to your knowledge","option_c":"join online courses","option_d":"live for a long time","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"The activity of setting up a business or businesses, taking on financial risk in the hope of profit is called _________","option_a":"Merchant","option_b":"Entrepreneurship","option_c":"Bank manager","option_d":"Sales executive","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"What encourages entrepreneurship on a grand scale?","option_a":"Become rich quickly","option_b":"Become famous","option_c":"Global leader","option_d":"New business opportunities","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"Find the Entrepreneur from the given options.","option_a":"RBI Governor","option_b":"SBI CEO","option_c":"Anand Mahindra","option_d":"Cabinet Secretary","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"The first version of a product/service is called _______","option_a":"model product","option_b":"first initiative","option_c":"prototype","option_d":"first edition","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What describes ʺHuman Resourcesʺ in a furniture manufacturing company?","option_a":"its products","option_b":"its sales record","option_c":"its profit","option_d":"its employees","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"What is the full form of GST?","option_a":"Government Sales Tax","option_b":"Goods Sales Tax","option_c":"Goods and Services Tax","option_d":"Government Service Tax","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"What is required to gather feedback from your customers?","option_a":"Advertisement on TV","option_b":"Brochure","option_c":"Billboards","option_d":"Market survey","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"An entrepreneurial mindset means to _______","option_a":"identify opportunities and Use them for your benefit","option_b":"not taking any risk","option_c":"not setting any goal","option_d":"think only about profit","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"What does it mean to think like a business person?","option_a":"Only thinking about money","option_b":"Being scared to try new things","option_c":"Seeing problems as things to fix","option_d":"Not liking change","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"If you face a problem, which of the following entrepreneurial mindset traits would be most helpful?","option_a":"Waiting until everything is perfect to do something","option_b":"Taking action to solve the problem","option_c":"Ignoring the problem and hoping it goes away","option_d":"Blaming others for the problem","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"If someone wants to sell homemade products, what do they have to do to grow the business?","option_a":"Find shopkeepers and build marketing relationships with them.","option_b":"Keep doing the same thing without any changes.","option_c":"Wait for an opportunity to grow the business.","option_d":"Sell only to neighbors.","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"If your coworkers donʹt agree with your project idea, whatʹs a good way to handle it with an entrepreneurial mindset?","option_a":"Give up on your idea","option_b":"Stop talking about it","option_c":"Ask for feedback and make your idea better with their help","option_d":"Stick to your idea without listening to others","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Why is it important to have a business plan before starting a business?","option_a":"To get loan from bank","option_b":"To show you are an entrepreneur","option_c":"To identify potential challenges with clear goal and risks","option_d":"Just a try","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"Imagine you are setting up a mobile repair shop. Which of the following is the most important for its success?","option_a":"Setting up the shop in a busy area","option_b":"Offering repair services at a higher price","option_c":"Putting up flyers in the neighbourhood","option_d":"Picking the right shop name","answer":"A","notes":""},{"question":"While making a business plan, which is not required to be mentioned?","option_a":"Business idea","option_b":"Startup costs","option_c":"Future growth strategies","option_d":"Personal interests and hobbies","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"If someone wants to apply for bank loan for their business, their business plan should have ________.","option_a":"only the idea and name of the business","option_b":"the total cost of the business without any details","option_c":"challenges about the business along with solutions","option_d":"business profit details","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"If you want to start a bakery business, what would you focus on first in your business plan?","option_a":"Selecting a catchy name for the bakery","option_b":"Calculating how much money you need to start the business","option_c":"Planning how to advertise the bakery on social media","option_d":"Figuring out how the business will grow","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While presenting your business plan to audience, how will you engage them to connect with you?","option_a":"Practice until you can confidently present your plan","option_b":"Repeat yourself multiple times","option_c":"Share a story or an experience that shaped your idea","option_d":"Avoid eye contact with the audience","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"When presenting your business plan to a potential investor, you should be clear about ________","option_a":"staff strength","option_b":"expected profit","option_c":"bank loan","option_d":"investment, expected customers, potential earnings","answer":"D","notes":""},{"question":"While talking about your business plan to the audience, how will you make them understand your product better?","option_a":"Repeat your explanation multiple times","option_b":"Give demo of the product/service","option_c":"Share overall business costs","option_d":"Tell a joke","answer":"B","notes":""},{"question":"While presenting your business plan to potential investors, why is it important to actively listen to their questions and provide thoughtful answers?","option_a":"To show off your expertise","option_b":"To avoid eye contact","option_c":"To understand the concerns of the investors and build their confidence in your plan","option_d":"To show your communication skills","answer":"C","notes":""},{"question":"When someone needs funding for a small business, what should they do to find a suitable investor?","option_a":"Start without funding and hope for an investor.","option_b":"Attend networking events to meet suitable investors.","option_c":"Send business plan to friends","option_d":"Wait for the suitable investor","answer":"B","notes":""}]}